<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="terrestrial">
    <title>Terrestrial Planets</title>
    <prolog>
        <metadata>
            <keywords>
                <indexterm>Planets<indexterm>Terrestrial</indexterm></indexterm>
                <indexterm>Terrestrial planets</indexterm>
                <indexterm>Terrestrial planets<indexterm>Mercury</indexterm></indexterm>
                <indexterm>Terrestrial planets<indexterm>Venus</indexterm></indexterm>
                <indexterm>Terrestrial planets<indexterm>Earth</indexterm></indexterm>
                <indexterm>Terrestrial planets<indexterm>Mares</indexterm></indexterm>
                <indexterm>Mercury</indexterm>
                <indexterm>Venus</indexterm>
                <indexterm>Earth</indexterm>
            </keywords>
        </metadata>
    </prolog>
    <body>
        <section id="mercury">
            <title>Mercury</title>
            <p><b>Mercury</b> is the smallest and innermost planet in the Solar System. Its orbital
                period around the Sun of 87.97 days is the shortest of all the planets in the Solar
                System. It is named after the Roman deity Mercury, the messenger of the gods.</p>
            <p>
                <fig id="fig2">
                    <title>Planet Mercury</title>
                    <image href="../img/Mercury.jpg"/>
                </fig>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="venus">
            <title>Venus</title>
            <p><b>Venus</b> is the second planet from the Sun, orbiting it every 224.7 Earth days.
                It has the longest rotation period (243 days) of any planet in the Solar System and
                rotates in the opposite direction to most other planets (meaning the Sun would rise
                in the west and set in the east). It does not have any natural satellites. It is
                named after the Roman goddess of love and beauty.</p>
            <p>
                <fig>
                    <title id="fig3">Planet Venus</title>
                    <image href="../img/Venus.jpg"/>
                </fig>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="earth">
            <title>Earth</title>
            <p><b>Earth</b> is the third planet from the Sun and the only astronomical object known
                to harbor life. According to radiometric dating and other sources of evidence, Earth
                formed over 4.5 billion years ago. Earth's gravity interacts with other objects in
                space, especially the Sun and the Moon, Earth's only natural satellite. Earth
                revolves around the Sun in 365.26 days, a period known as an Earth year. During this
                time, Earth rotates about its axis about 366.26 times.</p>
            <p>
                <fig id="fig4">
                    <title>Planet Earth</title>
                    <image href="../img/Earth.jpg"/>
                </fig>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="mars">
            <title>Mars</title>
            <p><b>Mars</b> is the fourth planet from the Sun and the second-smallest planet in the
                Solar System after Mercury. In English, Mars carries a name of the Roman god of war,
                and is often referred to as the "<b>Red Planet</b>" because the reddish iron oxide
                prevalent on its surface gives it a reddish appearance that is distinctive among the
                astronomical bodies visible to the naked eye. Mars is a terrestrial planet with a
                thin atmosphere, having surface features reminiscent both of the impact craters of
                the Moon and the valleys, deserts, and polar ice caps of Earth.</p>
            <p>
                <fig id="fig5">
                    <title>Planet Mars</title>
                    <image href="../img/Mars.jpg"/>
                </fig>
            </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</topic>
